WENHU CHEN

EL Colegio Rd, Santa Barbara, CA 93106

ABOUT ME

I'm a Ph.D. student in Computer Science Department of University of California, Santa Barbara supervised by Prof. William Wang and Xifeng Yan. My research interests lie in natural language processing and machine learning. Primarily, I work on sequence-to-sequence model, knowledge graph reasoning, and visual captioning. Secondarily, I'm broadly interested in task-oriented dialogue, Bayesian inference, and model compression.

PUBLICATIONS

Enhancing the Robustness of Prior Network in Out-of-Distribution Detection

Wenhu Chen, Yilin Shen, Xin Wang, William Yang Wang. Under Review

A Variational Dirichlet Framework for Out-of-Distribution Detection

Wenhu Chen, Yilin Shen, William Yang Wang, Hongxia Jin. Under Review

XL-NBT: A Cross-lingual Neural Belief Tracking Framework

Wenhu Chen, Jianshu Chen, Yu Su, Xin Wang, Dong Yu, Xifeng Yan and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of EMNLP 2018, Brussel, Belgium (Long Paper)

Triangular Architecture for Rare Language Translation

Shuo Ren, Wenhu Chen, Shujie Liu, Mu Li, Ming Zhou and Shuai Ma. Proceedings of ACL 2018, Melbourne, Australia (Long Oral)

No Metrics Are Perfect: Adversarial Reward Learning for Visual Storytelling

Wenhu Chen*, Xin Wang*, Yuan-Fang Wang and William Yang Wang. Proceedings of ACL 2018, Melbourne, Australia (Long Oral)

Variational Knowledge Graph Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, William Yang Wang, Xifeng Yan. Proceedings of NAACL 2018, New Orleans, CA (Long Oral)

Generative Bridging Network in Neural Sequence Prediction

Wenhu Chen, Guanlin Li, Shuo Ren, Shujie Liu, Zhirui Zhang, Mu Li, Ming Zhou. Proceedings of NAACL 2018, New Orleans, CA (Long Poster)

Video Captioning via Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning

Xin Wang, Wenhu Chen, Jiawei Wu, Yuan-fang Wang, William Yang Wang. Proceedings of CVPR 2018, Salt Lake City, UTAH (Poster)

Guided alignment training for topic-aware neural machine translation

Wenhu Chen, Evgeny Matusov, Shahram Khadivi, JT Peter. AMTA 2016, Austin, TX (Poster)

Facial Emotion Recognition Using PHOG and a Hierarchical Expression Model

Zhao Zhong, Gang Shen, Wenhu Chen. INCos 2013, IEEE

PATENTS & WORKSHOPS

A Joint Framework for Path Finding and Path Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, William Yang Wang, Xifeng Yan. KBCOM of WSDM 2018, Los Angeles, CA

Using meta-information in neural machine translation

Evgeny Matusov, Wenhu Chen, Shahram Khadivi. US Patent, 2017

SERVICE

Program Committee in Socal-NLP 2018

Program Committee in EMNLP 2018

Program Committee in AAAI 2019

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Barbara

Sep 2017-Now

Ph.D in Computer Science

Advisor: Xifeng Yan and William Wang

Overall GPA: 4.0/4.0

ETH Zurich, Switzerland

June 2016-Dec 2016

Visiting in Computer Science

Overall GPA: 6.0/6.0

RWTH Aachen University, Germany

Sep 2014-Dec 2016

M.S. in Electronics Engineering

Overall GPA: 1.4/1.0

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, China

Sep 2010-June 2014

M.S. in Electronics Engineering

Overall GPA: 86/100

EXPERIENCE

Research Intern

Samsung Research America

June 2018 - Sep 2018

Mountain View, USA

· Designed out-of-distribution detection algorithms

· Designed model compression algorithm for NLP tasks

Microsoft Research Asia

Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

Research Intern

Beijing, China

· Designed data-augmentation algorithm for sequence learning

· Designed new architecture for rare language translation

eBay Research Research Intern December 2015 - June 2016

Aachen, Germany

· Investigated the usage of statistical alignment in NMT

· Designed a meta-information based NMT system

Jinyin Dao Inc.

November 2011 - June 2012

Wuhan, China

 $Designer \ \mathcal{C} \ Developer$

· Worked on Android Software Development

· Designed user interface for an Android App

AWARD

IDEA Research Grant: Awarded IDEA research scholarship for exchange program in ETH.

German National Scholarship: Awarded a one-year scholarship sponsored by Robert Bosch Inc.

China Scholarship Committee Scholarship: Awarded full scholarship from CSC for a one-year exchange program in Germany.

MCM Finalist Award: Ranked top 0.5% in The Mathematical Contest in Modeling in 2013.